<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Filekseyos
f. 1r: Filəksəyos; (ፈልክስዮስ);</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <name>
         <namePart>
Unknown monk of the Gunda Gunde Monastery;</namePart>
         <role>
            <roleTerm type="text">creator</roleTerm>
         </role>
      </name>
      <name>
         <namePart/>
      </name>
      <genre>manuscript;</genre>
      <subject>
         <topic>Evagrius, Ponticus, 345?-399; Fathers of the church, Syriac.; Monasteries, monasticism and religious orders - Egypt;</topic>
      </subject>
      <subject>
         <temporal>18th Century
Gunda Gunde, Ethiopia</temporal>
      </subject>
      <note>f. 3ra-148va,16: Filəksəyos;  (ፈልክስዮስ); 
(title in the text: f. 3ra,8-11: History of the Fathers, Egyptian Monks, Holy Philoxenus the Syrian, bishop of Mabbog; f. 149ra-159ra,8: An excerpt from The Eight Evil Thoughts by Evagrius
2
(Wägris) of Pontus;</note>
      <originInfo>
         <publisher>Monastery of Gunda Gunde, Ethiopia
University of Toronto Scarborough Library; Hill Museum and Monastic Library, Collegeville, Minnesota</publisher>
      </originInfo>
      <originInfo>
         <dateOther>Unknown
2006-11-06</dateOther>
      </originInfo>
      <physicalDescription>
         <extent>159 + 1 (I); (European foliation);
16-19; difficult to count because the spine is covered with a leather cover;
2
Two wooden boards, each (and the spine) covered up to the middle with a leather cover;
Codex, 19 x 16.5 x 7 cm;
Vellum
4.43 GB
.tif</extent>
      </physicalDescription>
      <identifier type="local">GG-115</identifier>
      <relatedItem type="original">
         <titleInfo>
            <title>ooGG_115.tif</title>
         </titleInfo>
      </relatedItem>
      <relatedItem>
         <titleInfo>
            <title>2011-003
Gunda Gunde Manuscript Collection
Witakowski, Witold, ‘Filekseyus, the Ethiopic version of the Syriac Dadisho Qatraya’s Commentary on the Paradise of the Fathers’, [in:] Wälättä Yohanna: Ethiopian Studies in Honour of Joanna Mantel-Niecko on the Occasion of the 50th Year of Her Work at the Institute of Oriental Studies, Warsaw University, edited by Witold Witakowski and Laura Lykowska, Warsaw: Elipsa, 2006, (= Rocznik Orientalistyczny, 59:1 (2006)), pp. 281-296;</title>
         </titleInfo>
      </relatedItem>
      <language>
         <languageTerm type="text">Ge‘ez /Classical Ethiopic;</languageTerm>
      </language>
      <accessCondition>Professor Michael Gervers, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada, Ewa Balicka-Witakowska, Uppsala, Sweden,  and Father Columba Stewart, Hill Museum &amp; Manuscript Library, Saint John’s University, Minnesota, U.S.A</accessCondition>
   </mods>


